A Guide to the Papers of Thomas R. McNamara 1967-1976
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Series I: Legislative Files
  - Sub Series O: Legislative: Justice
    - Courts, Juvenile (General) 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Courts, Juvenile--Subcommittee Studying Carryover Bills Affecting Juveniles 1974 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Courts, Juvenile--"Comprehensive Long Range Master Plan For Juvenile and Youthful Offender Justice Systems in the Commonwealth of Virginia," 1974 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Crime Prevention (General), 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Crime Prevention--Department of State Police, Annual Report 1974 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Crime Prevention--"Law Enforcement in Virginia: A Descriptive Study," Volume I (Division of Justice and Crime Prevention) 1973 (Box-folder Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Crime Prevention--"Law Enforcement in Virginia: A Descriptive Study," Volume II( Division of Justice and Crime Prevention) 1973 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Crime Prevention--"Law Enforcement in Virginia: A Descriptive Study," Volume III (Division of Justice and Crime Prevention) 1974 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Crime Prevention--State Crime Commission (General) 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Crime Prevention--State Crime Commission Report 1973 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Crime Prevention--Annual Report of the Virginia State Crime Commission 1974 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Crime Prevention--Arson 1970 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Crime Prevention--Bad Check Losses (Senate Joint Resolution No. 11) 1972 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Crime Prevention--Cash Register Bill 1972 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Crime Prevention--Criminal Code Revision 1975 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Crime Prevention--Death in the Line of Duty Bill (includes special relief bill for Lewis Hurst, Jr.), 1967-1973 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Crime Prevention--Gun Control 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Crime Prevention--Scalping of Tickets 1970 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Crime Prevention--Victims, Compensation 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Crime Prevention--Wiretapping (Senate Bill No. 367) 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Bingo 1969-1973 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, State Lottery 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Pari-Mutuel Betting (General), 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Pari-Mutuel Betting (General) 1974 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Pari-Mutuel Betting (petitions in Opposition) (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Pari-Mutuel Report of Study Commission 1972 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Crime Prevention--Gambling, Pari-Mutuel Report of Study Commission 1974 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Eminent Domain Laws 1972 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Lawyers: State Bar Regulations 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Lawyers--Practice by Third Year Law Students 1974 (Box-folder Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Sub Series P: Legislative Correspondence: Transportation
    - General 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 54, Folder 1)
    - General--The Energy Crisis 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 54, Folder 2)
    - General--Noise Pollution Control and Abatement (NASA and Old Dominion University) 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Air (General) 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Air--Impact of Energy Crisis (Study by NASA and Old Dominion University) 1973 (Box-folder Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Automobile--General 1969-1974 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Automobile--Lesgilation 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Automobile--Virginia Highway Commission Reports includes Annual Reports and Financial Supplements 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Automobile--Virginia's Roads and Streets (VALC Reports) 1972-1982 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Automobile--Highway Construction Corresponce; Department of Highway Releases 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Automobile--Highway Construction, Department of Highways Reports re Allocation of Funds 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Automobile--Highway Construction, Department of Highways Reports on Allocation of Funds 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Automobile--Highway Safety--General 1967-1975 (Box-folder Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Automobile--Highway Safety--Highway Safety Division Reports 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Automobile--Highway Safety--Alcohol 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Automobile--Material re: Motor Vehicles 1968-1972 (Box-folder Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Automobile--Material re: Motor Vehicles 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Automobile--Motor Vehicle Repair in Virginia-Report of the Administrator for Consumer Affairs 1973 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Automobile--New Car Carriers Bill 1972 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Automobile--Transfer of Tunnel Commission Powers to Highway Commission includes Report on Estimated Traffic and Revenues for the Present and Proposed Elizabeth River Tunnels, De Leuw, Cather and Associates 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Automobile--Elizabeth River Tunnel Commission, S.R. 7692, S.R. 7694 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Mass Transit includes Southeastern Virginia Region Mass Transit Study, DeLeuw, Cather and Associates 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Railroads 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 57, Folder 6)
- Series II: Records of Service on the State Water Control Board
  - Sub Series A: Correpondence; Staff Communications
    - McNamara's Correspondence as Board Member 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with other Board Members 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Eugene Jensen, executive secretary of the Board includes "Groundwater Management in Southeastern Virginia and Northeastern North Carolina" prepared by North Carolina- Virginia Groundwater Subcommitte 1975 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence of Eugene Jensen, Copies 1975 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with State Water Control Board Staff 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Copies of Staff Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Communications from Staff to State Water Control Board, includes "Population Projections--Virginia Counties and Cities, 1980-2000" prepared by the Division of State Planning and Community Affairs May-July 1975 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Communications from Staff to State Water Control Board August, 1975 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Communications from Staff to State Water Control Board September-November, 1975 (Box-folder Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Communications from Staff to Board December 1975-January 1976 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Staff Activities Reports March, June, August 1975 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Staff Activities Reports October, December 1975 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda 3600-3620 May-June, 1975 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda 3621-3640 June-July, 1975 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda 3641-3660 (Incomplete) July-September 1975 (Box-folder Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda:3661-3680 (Incomplete) September-October, 1975 (Box-folder Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda:3681-3700 October-November, 1975 (Box-folder Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Letter Ballots, Memoranda: 3701-3717 (Incomplete) October 1975-January 1976 (Box-folder Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, Minutes March 1975 (Box-folder Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, Miscellaneous Material June, 1975 (Box-folder Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Meeting at Chincoteague September, 1975 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Meeting October, 1975 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Meeting January, 1976 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Staff Communications--Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Executive Orders 1975 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Material re: Budget 1975 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Budget Exhibit 1976-1978 (Box-folder Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Department of Commerce and Resources; Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Council on the Environment--Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Council on the Environment: Annual Report 1975 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Council on the Environment--Water Resources Committee 1975 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Legislation and Litigation: Correspondence re, May-October 1975 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Legislation and Litigation November-December 1975 (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Long Range Planning: General (Box-folder Box 62, Folder 7)
    - "Long Range Planning--Issues," a publication of the Virginia State Water Control Board June 1975 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 1)
    - "Long Range Planning--Goals," a publication of the Virginia State Water Control Board June 1975 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 2)
    - "Long Range Planning--Goals (2 copies) June 1975 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 3)
    - National Commission on Water Quality, Statement Prepared for Presentation Before January,1976 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission (General), 1975 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission-Miscellaneous Reports 1975 (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 6)
    - State Control Board: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission Personnel (Box-folder Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission: Engineering Meeting September 11, 1975 (Box-folder Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission: Meeting, Miscellaneous Materials January 1976 (Box-folder Box 64, Folder 2)
    - The Orsanco Story: Water Quality Management in the Ohio Valley under and Interstate Compact by Edward J.Cleary (Box-folder Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Personnel: Blazer-Zeni Report (Box-folder Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Priority System: General April-June 1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Priority System: General July-October 1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Priority System: Reports of Task Force 1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Priority System: Minutes--Meetings I May 6,9,1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Priority System: Minutes--Meetings II May 6,9 1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Priority System: Minutes of Hearings I December, 1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Priority System Minutes of Hearings II December,1975 (Box-folder Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Commission on State Governmental Management 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 1)
    - VEPCO Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Fibre Corporation, Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "Virginia Water Law: An Economic Appraisal, by Thomas T.Bergin 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 4)
    - "Water Quality Inventory--Virginia" Report to EPA Administrator and Congress, Information Bulletin 509 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Sub Series B: Projects
    - Projects: Atlantic Treatment Plant (Virginia Beach) 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Projects: Birchwood Gardens Sewage Treatment Plant (Virginia Beach) 1975 (Box-folder Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Blue Plains Aggreement 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Boat Pollution Control 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Boston Creek Reclassification 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Groundwater Act (Virginia)--Correspondence; Reports 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 4)
    - "Groundwater Conditions in the Eastern Shore of Virginia" SWCB Planning Bulletin 45 December 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Hampton Roads--General 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Hampton Roads Energy Corporation (Portsmouth, Virginia) 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Hampton Roads Sanitation District (General) includes Report on the Williamsburg Wastewater Treatment Plant August 1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Hampton Roads Water quality Agency Annual Report 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Isle of Wight--Nansemond includes "The Status of Ground-Water Resources Nansemond County and Isle of Wight County, Virginia 1975, 1967 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 1)
    - James River--Includes the final report on the Fish Kill in the lower James 1973 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 2)
    - James River Sewage Plant 1975 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Lake Tahoe Data 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Mecklenburg Prison Issue 1975 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Miller Brewing Company 1975 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 6)
    - New River, Report on Water Quality 1974 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Oak Ridge Estates 1975 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Occoquan Watershed Monitoring Program, Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Occoquan Watershed Monitoring Program Reports 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Potomac River Basin Compact--General 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Potomac River Basin Compact--P.R.B. Advisory Committee Material 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Potomac River Basin Compact, SWCB Staff Analysis 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Reybold Home, Inc. 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Richmond--Crater 208 Consortium 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke Area 208 Study 1975 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Southeastern Virginia Water Supply Problems 1975 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Twin Oaks Sewage Treatment Plant 1975 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Government--Aid to Sewage Facilities Construction (Talmage--Nunn Amendment) 1975 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Upper James River Basin--General includes "Upper James River Basin Water Quality Management Plan: Technical Supplement," 1975 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Upper James River Basin: Water Quality Management Plan 1976 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 5-8)
    - Upper James River Basin: Water Quality Management Plan 1976 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Wolf Creek Contamination (Town of Narrows, Virginia) 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 2)
    - York county Sewage Collection 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 3)
    - York River Basin--Water Quality Management 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 4)
    - U.S.Government--Environmental Protection Agency Study of Land Application Systems 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Government--Water Pollution Control 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Army Sewage study 1974 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Sub Series C: Newspaper Clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings September 1-17, 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings September 18-30, 1975 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings October 1-10, 1975 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings October 11-31, 1975 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings November, 1975 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings December 1-19, 1975 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings December 21-31, 1975 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings January, 1976 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 7)
- Series III: Political Papers
  - Sub Series A: Correspondence and Campaign Materials
    - General Correspondence 1967 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Catalogues, Correspondence 1967 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Bumper Stickers; Brochures 1967 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence 1968 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence; Newspaper clippings 1969 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence; Other Material 1970-1975 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Tidewater Delegation to the General Assembly 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Politicians Outside the Tidewater Area 1967-1970 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Henry E. Howell,Jr. 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Campaign spending: 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign February,1974 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Note Cards 1965-1967 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Poll for Jack Rixey 1968 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 4)
    - "The Men in the Mansion," by carl Shires, reprint of six articles on former Virginia governors published in the Richmond Newsleader October 2-7 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 5)
    - "The Virginia Constituency: Election District Data" 1970 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Votes by Ralph Eisenberg 1924-1968 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Votes For A New Constitution" by A.E. Dick Howard and Tim Finchem (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Material Re: Selection of Judges 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Material re: Virginia Democratic Party 1974 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence; Other Material 1973 (Box-folder Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Howell Involvement; Briefs, Decisions, Orders 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Clive DuVal Involvement, Briefs 1971 (Box-folder Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Standford E. Paris Involvement 1971 (Box-folder Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Commonwealth Pleadings 1971 (Box-folder Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Sub Series B: Speeches
    - Political: General Assembly Campaign May 8-June 20, 1967 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Political: General Assembly Campaign June 21-October 16, 1967 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Political: Introduction of Senator William Spong 1968 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Political: General Assembly Campaign 1969 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Political: 1971 Senatorial Campaign, Gubernatorial campaign of Mills E. Godwin 1971, 1973 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Non-Campaign 1968-1970 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Non-Campaign 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 76, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Newspaper Clippings
  - Miscellaneous 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 1)
  - General 1967 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Norfolk General Election 1967 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 3)
  - General Assembly Session, Politics 1968 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly Session; Budget Matters 1968 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Gubernatorial Campaign August 1969-November 1969 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Election Returns 1969 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Constitutional Revision-General Assembly Special Session 1969 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 8)
  - General 1969-1970 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 9)
  - General January-September 1974 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 10)
  - General October-December 1971 (Box-folder Box 77, Folder 11)
  - General Assembly (from Virginia Retail Merchants Association) 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 1)
  - General 1972 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Gubernatorial Campaign April 1973-September 1973 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Gubernatorial Campaign October 21, 1973-November 10, 1973 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 4)
  - General 1975 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Pari-Mutuel Betting 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Taxation--General 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 8)
  - McNamara Sales Tax Bills 1966-1970 (Box-folder Box 78, Folder 9)